Mai Thien Phuc (Bin)

Full Stack Web Developer

I am a dedicated and motivated individual with 3 years experience in both **front-end** and **back end development**, specializing in JavaScript, Typescript, React.js and Next.js. I have gained valuable knowledge through hands-on project work. I bring a passionate and enthusiasm for technology, and an strong commitment to continuous learning.

KEY SKILLS

- Programming Languages Javascript, Typescript, Java
- Frameworks React.js, Next.js, Bootstrap, Express.js, Node.js
- Database: MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase
- Devops CD/Cl Pipeline, Github Actions, GIT
- Design Figma, TailwindCSS, Material Design, Ant Design, Prime React

EXPERIENCE

SUPREME SPROUTS Feb 2024 - Present

Full Stack Web Developer

- Pioneer creating an application for company to take orders from their clients, clients order by submitting a form that match with their category and their needs.
- Technology Stacks: Typescript, Next.js, Prisma, MySQL, PlanetScale, TailwindCSS, Google Sheets API, RESTfulAPI, React-to-print
- · Create a backend server with integrating with Google Sheets by using Google Sheets API
- Optimize and restructure the API code with Nextjs and Prisma
- Create a customized middleware to guard all access to the API for both admin side and client side.
- Create user-friendly UI for both client side and admin side for managing their app and submit order with ease.

TRADE AND TRACK Dec 2023 - Mar 2024

Full Stack Web Developer Intern

- Design dark/light theme mode for the application using MUI theme config with React.js
- Create a month-view calendar using full-calendar library integrate with my written API for user to see their trade result
- Optimize and restructure the api code with Nextjs and Prisma
- Create a customized middleware to guard all access to the API.

PROJECTS

BookNook Jan 2024 - Mar 2024

- I manage 3 other people to work effectively in this project.
- This is the booking reservation app where customers can book a reservation at a restaurant with all the requirement they need, restaurant will receive and manage all of their reservations, tables, available time, etc with our user-friendly UI.
- Developing the UI and handle backend code for restaurant to be able to manage their tables and also their history reservations as well.
- Utilize user experience when calculate and fetch nearby restaurants based on customers' address by using Haversine method.
- Enhance the search capabilities to accommodate numerous options while ensuring that all restaurants meeting the criteria are accessible.
- Creating a logic to handle reservation booking and also allow customer to modify while ensuring the available time and date.

Technologies used: React.js, Vite, Firebase, Material UI

Version Control: Git

Github URL: https://github.com/PhucMaii/BookNook **Deployed Link**: https://book-nook-three.vercel.app/

GRAB & GO Aug 2023 - Present

- I use Firebase to store data and also it is a good place to store images of restaurants
- For better user experience, I use ApexChart.js to display their data or statistics using graphs
- To serve more people using my app, the app also includes i18.js. It currently has 3 languages support which are English, French
 and Vietnamese.
- PWA is a good technology to convert my website to a application thanks to service workers and caching methods

Technologies used: React.js, Firebase, ApexCharts.js, i18 (translation), PWA (Progressive Web Apps), Material UI, Stripe

Version Control: Git, also used git actions with CI/CD pipeline

Github URL: https://github.com/PhucMaii/RestaurantApp

Deploy URL: https://restaurant-app-git-dev-phucmaii.vercel.app/

EDUCATION KEY FEATURES

Diploma of Computer System Technology

Vancouver Community College (VCC)

Have legal status to work in Canada (Permanent Resident)Able to speak 2 languages fluently: Vietnamese and English